Full Stack Developer

renegrooth@gmail.com 0211802090

Auckland, New Zealand

Rene Groothuis

Profile

After working as an Electrician for 7 years on an expansive range of projects, I wanted to develop my problem-solving analytical and creative skills further. In order to improve on these skills I learnt as an electrician I have undertaken additional training and to refocus my skills towards Software Development.

I enjoyed the programming / problem solving side of being an Electrician so I commited to Software Devlopment by attending Dev Academy Aotearoa. In my new career I hope to continue solving complex problems with creativity and collaboration.

Experience

Apprentice Software Developer at Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

- This was a life-changing 17-week full-immersion software development bootcamp that closely represents working in a modern development team. The course taught me a modern development stack.
- Over these weeks I learnt JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, SQlite3 with knex, Node.js, Express.js.
- We worked in pairs, groups and solo to work on improving our technical skills and human skills to complete projects and assingments.
- During our final week we worked in a team of five to develop a web based app together. This was a 2D paltformer game we made using p5.js and react. In order to complete this project we learnt a new technology (p5) and applied it to what we had learned during the course. I have linked this project to the side.

Electrician at Prolectrics, Auckland

11/2018-12/2022

- Worked well independently and in a team to solve problems, working on multipule different projects that required a wide range of knowledge and organisation.
- Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.
- Organised and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Remained committed to adding to my knowledge and skills base, keeping up with the latest trends in the electrical space.
- Designed, planed, and executed new installs and regular maintenance for a wide range of customers.
- Work along side factorys to maintain, diagnose and repair machines, including upgrading safety systems, installing new circuits and testing and repairing emergency systems.

Electrician Apprentice at ETCO, Auckland

08/2016-11/2018

Did my apprenticeship training through ETCO where we worked with different companies to learn a wide range of electrical skills. Including residential, commercial and industrial.

Education

Links

GitHub LinkedIn Personal Website Final Project for Dev Academy

Skills

Typescript
React
Redux
Node.js
SQlite3
Ability to Work in a Team
Computer Skills
Electrical Wiring
Troubleshooting
Safe Work Practices

Hobbies

In my spare time I enjoy running, going to the gym, football and skiing in winter

References

References available upon request

Level 6 Applied Technology of Software Development, Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

An intensive 17-week web development training program that replicates real industry work with a focus on technical and non-technical skills.

Level 4 Electrical Engineering, ETCO, Auckland

01/2017-11/2019

New Zealand Certificate in Electrical Engineering Theory and Practice (Trade) (Level 4).